American Institute of Architects: Waco Chapter records, Inclusive: 1962-1971
Baylor University, The Texas Collection
American Institute of Architects: Waco Chapter records
Inclusive: 1962-1971
Baylor University, The Texas Collection http://www.baylor.edu/lib/texas/
240
American Institute of Architects. Waco Chapter.
1 document box
The American Institute of Architects: Waco Chapter records provide insight into the organization from its inception in 1962 until 1971. Materials include meeting minutes, membership applications, support documents issued by the national organization, correspondence, and financial documents.
Administrative Information
Physical Description
General condition: Excellent.
Biography/Profile
The American Institute of Architects (AIA) Waco Chapter is a local chapter of the Texas Society of Architects affiliated with national AIA. Until the 1960's, Waco area architects were affiliated with larger chapters including Austin, Brazos, Dallas, and Fort Worth. In 1962, the Waco Chapter began meeting and worked with the state of Texas to become independent. This involved the release of several counties from their respective chapters to accomplish. Early counties included Bell, Falls, Limestone, and McLennan.
On April 22, 1965, Waco was officially chartered as a chapter of the American Institute of Architects. The organization provided local professionals educational opportunities and regular programs. The chapter was also able to send delegates to the state business meeting.
In 1984, the chapter established a scholarship, AIA Waco Chapter Memorial Scholarship, for students from the chapter area pursuing architectural degrees. Although the chapter is no longer active, the scholarship is administered by the chapter successor, the AIA Waco Section. A section differs from a chapter in that it does not have a voting presence at the state level.
Scope and Content
The American Institute of Architects: Waco Chapter records contains three series; Administrative, Correspondence, and Financial.The Administrative series includes meeting minutes which show creation and charter of chapter and provides insight into the Waco architects of the time and their activities and professional goals. Chapter membership applications share valuable info on area architects and different types of membership available in the parent AIA organization. National membership includes guidelines, reports, national board minutes, policies and procedures and other materials for use by the chapter.
Correspondence includes general business of the chapter. Information on membership and meeting programs is the bulk of this series. The Financial series is the contents of a file marked “Treasurer’s Report.” It consists of bank statements and returned checks which were kept as monetary record of the chapter as it chronicles chapter expenses beyond member dues.
Arrangement
Material in this collection was previously organized by material type which guided current arrangement in the following series: I. Administrative, II. Correspondence, III. Financial.
Access Restrictions
All requests for copying of materials must be submitted to The Texas Collection in writing. Please use the Request Form for Copying Materials sheet. Unpublished materials authored or otherwise produced by the creator (s) of this collection are in the public domain. There are no restrictions on use. Copyright status for other collection materials is unknown. Transmission or reproduction of materials protected by U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) beyond that allowed by fair use requires the written permission of the copyright owners. Works not in the public domain cannot be commercially exploited without permission of the copyright owners. Responsibility for any use rests exclusively with the user.
Acquisition Information
Accession No. 240. Acquired 1971-00-00
Related Resources
Related references
“AIA Waco Chapter Memorial Scholarship.” College of Architecture, Texas A&M University. Accessed 2020 March 19.
“Architecture and Interior Design Scholarships.” CAPPA, University of Texas at Arlington. Accessed 2020 March 19.
Index Terms
Subjects
American Institute of Architects -- Waco Chapter.; Architects -- Texas.
Genres
Correspondence.; Minutes (Records); Records (Documents)
- Administrative, 1962-1970; 1
  Administrative Information
  Physical Description
  General condition: Excellent.
  Biography/Profile
  The Administrative series is dated 1962-1970 and includes meeting minutes and membership information at the local and national levels. The series is organized in chronological order and in good condition.
  - Minutes, 1962-1970 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Membership: Chapter, 1963-1970 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Membership: National (1 of 3), 1966-1969 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Membership: National (2 of 3), 1966-1969 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Membership: National (3 of 3), 1966-1969 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Correspondence, 1962-1971; 2
  The Correspondence series, dated 1962-1971, includes notes about membership, general chapter business, and presentations. The series is organized chronologically and is in good condition.
  - General, 1962-1965 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - General, 1966-1968 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - General, 1969-1971 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Financial, 1963-1970; 3
  The Financial series is dated 1963-1970 and includes bank statements and cancelled checks. It is organized chronologically and in good condition.
  - Treasurer’s Reports (1 of 2), 1963-1970 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Treasurer’s Reports (2 of 2), 1963-1970 (Box 1, Folder 10)